<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>awakening</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-06-30T06:51:03.479Z</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>John Doe</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Chinese Police Step Up Phone Checks, Using Surveillance Apps</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index005/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index005/</id>
    <published>2019-06-30T05:57:52.118Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-30T06:51:03.479Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/27/GettyImages-464927456-700x420.jpg" alt="Chinese police question a man (C) in Tiananmen Square, next to the Great Hall of the People, the venue for upcoming meetings of China's legislature in Beijing on March 2, 2015. (GREG BAKER/AFP/Getty Images)"><div class="featured_caption">Chinese police question a man (C) in Tiananmen Square, next to the Great Hall of the People, the venue for upcoming meetings of China's legislature in Beijing on March 2, 2015. (GREG BAKER/AFP/Getty Images)</div><a id="more"></a><div class="post_content">                    <p>Chinese netizens recently reported that <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-police" target="_blank">police</a> have begun checking people’s smartphones with a special mobile device at subway stations and on the streets of Beijing and Shanghai.</p><p>Beijing police said that the tool is only for scanning people’s IDs, but netizens and experts who dug deeper have discovered that the product can extract personal data from smartphones without authorization from the smartphone owner.</p><h2><strong>Checkpoints</strong></h2><p>A Beijing netizen sent a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P30reg0GFOs" target="_blank">video</a> to the Chinese-language Epoch Times on June 17, which showed that Beijing police have set up a temporary checkpoint at the Dongzhimen Subway Station to check travelers’ smartphones.</p><p>“The police is checking everything on the phone,” the person shooting the video can be heard saying.</p><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_5YQ9"></div></div><p>Ms. Cheng, a Shanghai dissident, also <a href="https://www.ntdtv.com/b5/2019/06/21/a102605970.html" target="_blank">told</a> U.S.-based broadcaster and sister media NTD that local police on the streets have also begun checking people’s phones.</p><p>Several netizens from Shanghai and Beijing told NTD that the police mainly check whether there are photos or videos about recent Hong Kong protests against a controversial extradition bill, a topic banned in mainland <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-china" target="_blank">China</a>. The police also look for whether people have installed virtual private network (VPN) and other apps that can allow users to bypass the Chinese firewall and access foreign websites that are banned inside China.</p><p>On June 21, the Beijing police department published a statement on its official Weibo account, denying netizens’ complaints that officers were accessing people’s smartphones.</p><p>In the <a href="https://www.weibo.com/ttarticle/p/show?id=2309404385569965777626" target="_blank">statement</a>, it said that the police did not take away people’s smartphones, but were using their “mobile police terminals” to check IDs.</p><h2><strong>Surveillance Tool</strong></h2><p>The statement also explained what the device does: “Police can use this ‘smartphone’ [mobile police terminal] to accomplish all types of police work. This device is the perfect embodiment of advanced police technology as well as applying big data.”</p><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_O8JB"></div></div><p>“Mobile police terminal” devices have proliferated in certain years. Many software developers tout their success at scoring government clients.</p><p><a href="http://www.xdja.com/index.php/Index/detail/id/565.html" target="_blank">Xinda Jie’an</a>, for example, said on its website that its devices for police in Henan Province can identify people’s faces after taking their photo. All their background information will then become available to police, including contact information, any prior criminal record, cars and other vehicles that are registered under the person, and so on.</p><p>For foreigners, their profiles and passport numbers can be accessed after police can take a photo or a finger scan with the device. The police can also input more information about the foreigner’s behavior into the database.</p><p>In the northwestern region of Xinjiang, where the resident Uyghur population is closely monitored by authorities, <a href="https://www.hikvision.com/uploadfile/image/20151028035014008.PDF" target="_blank">Hikvision</a>-developed devices can connect the police network via any mobile carrier, allowing police to upload and download data from people’s phones and into the police database.</p><p>Meanwhile, <a href="http://www.vickn.com/Solution/detail/58" target="_blank">Vickn</a>, a developer of mobile communication-based security software, uses hardware manufactured by Chinese tech giant Huawei to operate its police devices. According to its website, Vickn supplies to police in Jiangsu, Ningxia, Guangxi, Guizhou, and Sichuan provinces.</p><p>According to Vickn’s product <a href="http://www.vickn.com/Solution/detail/52" target="_blank">page</a>, its mobile police terminal can identify people by scanning their fingerprints. Police can then access the person’s file on its database, which includes information on their homes.</p><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_O8JB_1"></div></div><h2><strong>Surveillance App</strong></h2><p>Since 2016, netizens have <a href="https://bbs.pediy.com/thread-212499.htm" target="_blank">complained</a> that after police checked their phones, a MFsocket app mysteriously appears on their phones. They are unable to uninstall it.</p><p>Recently, netizens again <a href="https://pincong.rocks/question/5003" target="_blank">reported</a> this phenomenon.</p><p>On June 25, a French cybersecurity engineer and vigilante hacker who uses the pseudonym Elliot Alderson, published his research findings on the MFsocket app on <a href="https://medium.com/@fs0c131y/mfsocket-a-chinese-surveillance-tool-58e8850c3de4" target="_blank">Medium.com</a>.</p><p>Alderson found out: “[MFsocket] is asking a lot of dangerous permissions: – Read your call log, your contacts, your SMS, your calendar, your SD card – Disable the lock screen – Access your location – install a new app without your consent.”</p><p>“Moreover, we can see that the activity doesn’t have the category launcher which means that this app doesn’t have an icon,” Alderson wrote.</p><p>He concluded that the app was a <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-surveillance" target="_blank">surveillance</a> tool.</p><p><em>This article previously misreported where the hacker self-identified as&nbsp;Elliot Alderson was based. The Epoch Times regrets the error.</em></p><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_zJgm"></div></div>                <div class="article-below-offers under-article-container desktop piano-templates standard"></div><div class="article-below-widgets under-article-container desktop widget-cloud-loaders standard"></div></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/27/GettyImages-464927456-700x420.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chinese police question a man (C) in Tiananmen Square, next to the Great Hall of the People, the venue for upcoming meetings of China&#39;s legislature in Beijing on March 2, 2015. (GREG BAKER/AFP/Getty Images)&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;featured_caption&quot;&gt;Chinese police question a man (C) in Tiananmen Square, next to the Great Hall of the People, the venue for upcoming meetings of China&#39;s legislature in Beijing on March 2, 2015. (GREG BAKER/AFP/Getty Images)&lt;/div&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Wife Sees Jailed Chinese Rights Lawyer For First Time in 4 Years, Says He’s a ‘Changed Person’</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index004/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index004/</id>
    <published>2019-06-30T05:53:01.399Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-30T05:56:29.728Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/01/28/Wang-Quanzhang-1.jpg" alt="Wang Quanzhang with his wife, Li Wenzu, and their son. Wang Quanzhang, a human rights lawyer, has been detained in China without trial since August 2015. (Courtesy of Li Wenzu)"><div class="featured_caption">Wang Quanzhang with his wife, Li Wenzu, and their son. Wang Quanzhang, a human rights lawyer, has been detained in China without trial since August 2015. (Courtesy of Li Wenzu)</div><a id="more"></a><div class="post_content"><p>It was a long-awaited meeting for both.</p><p>Li Wenzu had not seen her husband, <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-wang-quanzhang" target="_blank">Wang Quanzhang</a>, since the Chinese <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-lawyer" target="_blank">lawyer</a> was jailed for his <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-t-human-rights" target="_blank">human rights</a> advocacy four years ago. Chinese authorities have continuously denied her visitation rights. She would often travel to the <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-prison" target="_blank">prison</a> he was detained at, and <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/jailed-chinese-human-rights-lawyer-promised-first-family-visit-after-four-years-of-detention_2978484.html" target="_blank">call his name from outside the prison wall</a>, in the hopes that he could hear.</p><p>Since five years ago, when Wang was arrested and detained by Chinese authorities amid a nationwide crackdown of human rights lawyers and activists in July 2015, Li had been waiting to see her husband’s face. The day before Li’s first-ever scheduled prison visit on June 28, she wrote on Twitter that “the waiting time was so dragged-out.”</p><p>After traveling nearly 420 miles from Beijing to the Linyi Prison in Shandong Province, Li found the half-hour meeting nothing like what she expected.</p><p>The prison deployed hundreds of police outside.</p><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_5YQ9"></div></div><p>As Li walked into the reception room with her 6-year-old son, Quanquan, she had to pause for a moment before she could recognize the man. Sitting across the glass window was a thinner, older, and wearier-looking version of her husband.</p><a href="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/01/30/wang-wanzhou-china-rights-lawyer.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="lazy size-medium wp-image-2784561 ll-init ll-notloaded" src="https://www.theepochtimes.com/assets/themes/eet/images/white.png" data-src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/01/30/wang-wanzhou-china-rights-lawyer-600x337.jpg" alt width="600" height="337"></a><a href="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/01/30/wang-wanzhou-china-rights-lawyer.jpg" target="_blank"><noscript><img src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/01/30/wang-wanzhou-china-rights-lawyer-600x337.jpg" alt width="600" height="337"></noscript></a> Wang Quanzhang was detained in 2015 and sentenced on Jan. 28, 2019. (Photo from Wang’s family)<h2>Changed Person</h2><p>Li said that both Wang’s personality and appearance had changed so much that she would not have recognized him had they met on the street.</p><p>“I smiled and waved to him in excitement, but he glanced at me without any expression, and tilted his head to the side without looking at me,” Li wrote in a tweet after their meeting.</p><p>In an interview on June 28, Li recounted to The Epoch Times how their meeting went. She said he appeared happy upon seeing their son, but a sense of worry soon clouded his face.</p><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_O8JB"></div></div><p>“He wasn’t in a good state, I could tell that he was under extreme stress and fear. We couldn’t even have a conversation,” Li said.</p><p>Li said that Wang was anxious about her safety. “He expressed concerns that I would be arrested, that our child would be forced out of school.”</p><p>“He asked me not to visit him in the next few months,” Li said.</p><p>Li noted that he appeared easily agitated and had difficulty remembering recent events.</p><p>When Quanquan asked his father whether he had been eating well, Wang said slowly in a robotic voice that he had everything he needed, including extra food. When Li asked what the “extras” were, he began to scratch his head with a troubled look and repeated the question to himself.</p><p>“I’m fine, the prison has been treating me very well, it’s not like what you guys think,” Wang said in a high tone, claiming that he had put on weight while in prison, Li recalled in her tweet.</p><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_O8JB_1"></div></div><p>“Tears streamed down as I looked at the thinned face of Quanzhang … His two front teeth that used to be neatly aligned now shows a huge space in between,” she wrote, adding that Wang seemed like a totally different person. “He looked at me … as if looking at a stranger and not the wife he hasn’t seen for four years.”</p><p>Li also said she had never heard him speak in that aggressive tone. “He wasn’t like that before, Quanzhang was a mild person,” Li said. “He never lost his temper in front of me.”</p><p>When the guards ended the meeting, Wang walked away without looking back at them.</p><p>She observed that five or six guards were monitoring them as they spoke, with another taking notes beside Wang throughout the visit. Another guard was also filming them on a camcorder, according to Li.</p><figure id="attachment_2982891" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/28/li-wenzu.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="lazy size-large wp-image-2982891 ll-init ll-notloaded" src="https://www.theepochtimes.com/assets/themes/eet/images/white.png" data-src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/28/li-wenzu-1200x800.jpg" alt="li wenzu wang quanzhang" width="640" height="427"></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><a href="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/28/li-wenzu.jpg" target="_blank"><noscript><img class="size-large wp-image-2982891" src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/28/li-wenzu-1200x800.jpg" alt="li wenzu wang quanzhang" width="640" height="427"></noscript></a> Li Wenzu (L), the wife of detained human rights lawyer Wang Quanzhang, walks on the outskirts of Beijing to Tianjin, where she believes her husband is being held, on April 5, 2018.&nbsp;(Greg Baker/AFP/Getty Images)</figcaption></figure><h2>Controlling One’s Mind</h2><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_O8JB_2"></div></div><p>After he was taken away by police amid the nationwide crackdown, known as the 709 Incident, he was detained for roughly three years. On Jan. 28 this year, in a closed-door trial, Wang was sentenced to four and a half years in prison on charges of subversion—a euphemism for activism that draws the Chinese regime’s ire. In seeking Wang’s release and her visitation rights, Li has met with government officials from different countries, including German Chancellor Angela Merkel and U.K. Ambassador to China Barbara Woodward.</p><p></p><twitter-widget class="twitter-tweet twitter-tweet-rendered" id="twitter-widget-0" style="position: static; visibility: visible; display: block; transform: rotate(0deg); max-width: 100%; width: 500px; min-width: 220px; margin-top: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;" data-tweet-id="1138768969773400064"></twitter-widget><p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p><p></p><p><a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-chen-guangcheng" target="_blank">Chen Guangcheng</a>, a Chinese human rights lawyer and civil rights activist, told The Epoch Times that the goal of the Chinese Communist Party was to control their thoughts. He suggested that Chinese authorities likely arranged the meeting between Wang and Li so that the sense of desperation and fear would spread from Wang to his family—and stop them from being vocal about his case.</p><a href="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/28/chen-guangcheng.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="lazy size-large wp-image-2982875 ll-init ll-notloaded" src="https://www.theepochtimes.com/assets/themes/eet/images/white.png" data-src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/28/chen-guangcheng-1200x794.jpg" alt="Chinese Activist Chen Guangcheng Receives The Tom Lantos Human Rights Award" width="640" height="423"></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><a href="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/28/chen-guangcheng.jpg" target="_blank"><noscript><img class="size-large wp-image-2982875" src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/28/chen-guangcheng-1200x794.jpg" alt="Chinese Activist Chen Guangcheng Receives The Tom Lantos Human Rights Award" width="640" height="423"></noscript></a> Chinese human rights activist Chen Guangcheng (3rd L) stands with his wife Yua Weijing (3rd R) following a ceremony where he was presented the Tom Lantos Human Rights Prize in Washington, on Jan. 29, 2013. (Win McNamee/Getty Images)</figcaption><p>Chen fled China to the United States in 2012 with the help of U.S. officials. He had been under house arrest before he planned a daring escape to the U.S. embassy in Beijing.</p><p>Speaking from his personal experience, Chen said when suppressing dissidents, the Chinese regime often plays with their fears while they are detained in a secluded environment, seeking to inflict mental pressure.</p><p>“If you don’t cave in, they would use all kinds of ways to ‘educate’ you with fear and threats,” Chen said.</p><p>“They instill this kind of fear in you, and you don’t know any other information nor the true situation. This will prey on your mind.”</p><p>Chen said that their ultimate goal was to wear them out until “you no longer care about the injustices in society and just live your life,” Chen said. “They want the shackles to be secured in Li Wenzu and Wang Quanzhang’s minds for the rest of their lives.”</p><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_zJgm"></div></div><span class="author_twitter">Follow Eva on Twitter: <a class="author_twitter_link" href="https://twitter.com/EvaSailEast" target="_blank">@EvaSailEast</a></span>                <div class="article-below-offers under-article-container desktop piano-templates standard"></div><div class="article-below-widgets under-article-container desktop widget-cloud-loaders standard"></div></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/01/28/Wang-Quanzhang-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wang Quanzhang with his wife, Li Wenzu, and their son. Wang Quanzhang, a human rights lawyer, has been detained in China without trial since August 2015. (Courtesy of Li Wenzu)&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;featured_caption&quot;&gt;Wang Quanzhang with his wife, Li Wenzu, and their son. Wang Quanzhang, a human rights lawyer, has been detained in China without trial since August 2015. (Courtesy of Li Wenzu)&lt;/div&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Second Hong Kong Protester Falls to Death, Leaves Message Opposing Extradition Bill</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index003/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index003/</id>
    <published>2019-06-30T05:44:15.469Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-30T05:50:08.200Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/19/HK-June-19-0001-700x420.jpg" alt="Protesters occupy a street demanding Hong Kong leader to step down after a rally against the now-suspended extradition bill outside of the Chief Executive Office in Hong Kong on June 17, 2019. (Anthony Kwan/Getty Images)"><a id="more"></a><div class="post_content">                    <p>A 21-year-old student has died after falling from a building in <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-hong-kong" target="_blank">Hong Kong</a> on June 29, after leaving an apparent message on the staircase protesting the city’s recent controversial <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-extradition" target="_blank">extradition</a> bill, local media reported.</p><p>Lo Hiu-yan, a first-year female student studying arts at Education University, left a 91-word message at an upper-floor staircase of Fuk Tai building in Fanling, Hong Kong, calling for the complete withdrawal of the extradition bill, along with other demands urged by millions of Hongkongers.</p><p>Over the past few weeks millions of people have taken to the city’s streets to <a href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/t-protest" target="_blank">protest</a> a proposed extradition law that would allow people to be transferred to mainland China for trial. Opponents say that given the Chinese regime doesn’t operate under the rule of law, the bill would enable it to seek the extradition of its critics in Hong Kong with impunity.</p><p>The student fell from the building around 4 p.m. local time on June 29 and was confirmed dead at the scene by ambulance crew, according to Hong Kong media <a href="https://hk.news.appledaily.com/breaking/realtime/article/20190629/59771130" target="_blank">Apple Daily</a>. Unnamed sources told the outlet she had previously participated in anti-extradition-bill protests.</p><p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_5YQ9"></div></div><p></p><p>According to Apple Daily, her message on the wall, written in red and addressed to Hongkongers, read: “Although we have been fighting for a long time, we must not forget our beliefs from the very beginning and must keep persisting.</p><p>“[We] strongly demand the complete withdrawal of the [extradition] bill, the retraction of the labeling [of a June 12 demonstration] as a ‘riot,’ the release of [arrested] student demonstrators, the resignation of [Hong Kong leader] Carrie Lam, and the punishment of the police.”</p><p>The message ended with the line: “I hope to exchange my life for the fulfillment of two million people’s wishes. Please continue to persevere, you all.”</p><p>Lo also posted a picture of her message on the wall to her Instagram page, Apple Daily reported. Police have since covered her written message with a black sheet, the outlet added. Lo was not a resident of the building.</p><p>Over a hundred mourners laid flowers and notes at the scene in remembrance of Lo as of the evening of June 29. Students at Education University, where Lo had attended, will hold a mourning ceremony for Lo on June 30.</p><figure id="attachment_2983636" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/29/No-extradition-protester-on-scaffolding.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="lazy size-medium wp-image-2983636 ll-init ll-notloaded" src="https://www.theepochtimes.com/assets/themes/eet/images/white.png" data-src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/29/No-extradition-protester-on-scaffolding-600x400.jpg" alt width="600" height="400"></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><a href="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/29/No-extradition-protester-on-scaffolding.jpg" target="_blank"><noscript><img class="size-medium wp-image-2983636" src="https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/29/No-extradition-protester-on-scaffolding-600x400.jpg" alt width="600" height="400"></noscript></a> A person stands on a scaffolding surrounding the Pacific Place complex next to a banner related to the protests against the proposed extradition bill, in Hong Kong, China, June 15, 2019. REUTERS/Athit Perawongmetha</figcaption></figure><p>This is not the first death associated with the protests. On June 15, a 35-year-old man in a yellow raincoat died after unfurling a banner protesting the proposed extradition laws from the side of a shopping mall in Admiralty.</p><p>The man, wearing a yellow raincoat, called for the complete withdrawal of the extradition bill and for Hong Kong Leader Carrie Lam to step down. Written on the back of his raincoat was “Carrie Lam Kills Hong Kong.”</p><p>Hongkongers mourned the man in the following weeks. Many left tributes to him with flowers and notes at the scene, and some showed up in yellow raincoats in later protests.</p><p><em>If you or someone you know is showing signs that they might be considering suicide, the suicide prevention hotline is available 24-7 for those in Hong Kong at 2382 0000. For urgent assistance, call 999.</em></p><p><em>Those in the United States can call 800-273-TALK or go to suicidepreventionlifeline.org. Texts can also be sent to The Crisis Text Line at 741 741.</em></p><div style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 25px; text-align: center"><div id="RTK_zJgm"></div></div><div class="article-below-offers under-article-container desktop piano-templates standard"></div><div class="article-below-widgets under-article-container desktop widget-cloud-loaders standard"></div></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.theepochtimes.com/assets/uploads/2019/06/19/HK-June-19-0001-700x420.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Protesters occupy a street demanding Hong Kong leader to step down after a rally against the now-suspended extradition bill outside of the Chief Executive Office in Hong Kong on June 17, 2019. (Anthony Kwan/Getty Images)&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Chinese Rights Lawyer Demoted From Teaching Post at Shandong University</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index002/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index002/</id>
    <published>2019-06-30T05:19:56.309Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-30T05:38:49.952Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/demoted-05092019112822.html/china-liushuqing2-050919.jpg/image" alt="Rights lawyer and university lecturer Liu Shuqing is shown in an undated photo." title="Rights lawyer and university lecturer Liu Shuqing is shown in an undated photo." height="349" width="620"><a id="more"></a><div id="headerimgcontents">  <div id="headerimgcaption"> <span>Rights lawyer and university lecturer Liu Shuqing is shown in an undated photo.</span><p>A university in the eastern Chinese province of Shandong has fired a lecturer and human rights lawyer after he "repeatedly published inappropriate comments" in the media, RFA has learned.<br><br>Rights lawyer Liu Shuqing, who also works at a public interest law firm, was told to stop teaching classes at the Shandong Qilu University of Technology last year.<br><br>The university issued a statement accusing Liu of "violating teaching standards of practice" and being a "bad influence."<br><br>Liu, who was hired to teach by the college's school of chemical engineering, said he had also been rated "unqualified" in a recent staff assessment, although he was the only one in his faculty to fail his assessment.<br><br>The school will now go through a disciplinary process based on two posts he made on the internet, about a government grading system for lawyers and the abuse of official power.<br><br>But he said he had never discussed his opinions while teaching, and that there was nothing illegal in either post.<br><br>"I told them that teaching is only one of my professions, but that my identity is as a citizen, and that citizens have the right to freedom of speech," Liu told RFA.<br><br>"Both of these posts are still on WeChat, and haven't been blocked or deleted," he said. "I am very disappointed that the school has punished me anyway."<br><br><b>Not yet fired</b><br><br>Liu has already been ordered to stop teaching, but hasn't been formally fired. Instead, he has been demoted to the status of teaching assistant.<br><br>His contract states that the university can fire him if he fails two consecutive annual assessments, however.<br><br>"I have been teaching for more than 10 years," Liu told RFA. "I think I am a very competent teacher. I am qualified ... It is very unfair."<br><br>He said he would see whether or not the school would accept an offer of arbitration, as hinted at in their letter informing him of the decision.<br><br>An employee who answered the phone at the university's personnel department declined to comment.<br><br>"I don't know this teacher, and I'm not familiar with the case," the employee said. "You should call the propaganda department."<br><br><b>Growing censorship</b><br><br>Academics say the ruling Chinese Communist Party is stepping up its censorship of academics in an unconstitutional bid to silence even the mildest criticism.<br><br>Former Guizhou University professor Yang Shaozheng, who was fired outright after he made comments critical of the Communist Party in an online article, said self-censorship in colleges and universities is a growing problem on Chinese campuses.<br><br>"What it means is that no one in this society is willing to insist on justice and the rule of law," Yang said. "They are forcing teachers and other members of society to stay silent about whatever they think is problematic."<br><br>"If you go on like this for a long time, this country will lose its sense of right and wrong."<br><br>Liu has previously represented Beijing rights lawyer Wang Yu, who was the first of hundreds to be detained and sanctioned in a nationwide crackdown launched in July 2015.<br><br>He has also counted New Citizens' Movement found Xu Zhiyong, Harbin petitioner Xu Chunhe, and many other rights activists among his clients.<br><br><b>'Political training'</b><br><br>Earlier this week, China's education ministry launched a new wave of political training for colleges and universities that aims to instill the ideology of President Xi Jinping and late supreme leader Mao Zedong in staff and students alike.<br><br>The Ministry of Education released on Monday a five-year training plan for teachers via a series of "political theory" courses in colleges and universities.<br><br>According to the ministry, "it is necessary to train dozens of ideological and political scholars with extensive influence ... as well as hundreds of leaders in ideological and political education."<br><br>Under the plan, thousands of teachers and professors will study the classics of Marxism alongside the Thought of Xi Jinping, Mao Zedong, and late supreme leader Deng Xiaoping.<br><br>The results of their theoretical research should then be integrated into their teaching materials, the ministry said.<br><br>All colleges and universities will be required to send at least two qualified teachers to participate in the program, achieving full coverage of all Chinese tertiary institutions within five years, it said.<br><br><i><b>Reported by Gao Feng for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by Wen Yuqing for the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p></div></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/demoted-05092019112822.html/china-liushuqing2-050919.jpg/image&quot; alt=&quot;Rights lawyer and university lecturer Liu Shuqing is shown in an undated photo.&quot; title=&quot;Rights lawyer and university lecturer Liu Shuqing is shown in an undated photo.&quot; height=&quot;349&quot; width=&quot;620&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Former Interpol Chief Stands Trial For Bribery in China&#39;s Tianjin</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index001/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index001/</id>
    <published>2019-06-30T04:58:42.318Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-30T05:12:47.582Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/trial-06202019111503.html/china-meng-hongwei-trial-june-2019.jpg/@@images/b7411214-8902-49bd-933e-eafb0e0e43cb.jpeg" alt="This handout photo released by the Tianjin No. 1 Intermediate Court shows former Interpol chief Meng Hongwei (C) during his trial at the court in Tianjin, June 20, 2019." title="This handout photo released by the Tianjin No. 1 Intermediate Court shows former Interpol chief Meng Hongwei (C) during his trial at the court in Tianjin, June 20, 2019." height="350" width="622"><a id="more"></a><p>Former Interpol president Meng Hongwei stood trial in the northern Chinese city of Tianjin on Thursday, as his wife said she wasn't sure the man presented on state media footage was her husband.<br><br>Meng "confessed" to accepting more than U.S. $2 million in bribes and expressed regret for his crime, the Tianjin No. 1 Intermediate People's Court said in a statement.<br><br>Official footage of the trial aired by state broadcaster CCTV showed Meng in a beige jacket standing between two police officers in a court, with a small group of people sitting behind him.<br><br>According to the indictment, the charges relate to Meng's tenure as minister, vice-minister and ruling Chinese Communist Party secretary for public security, and as head of the Chinese marine police, between 2005 and 2017.<br><br>Chengdu-based rights activist Chen Yunfei said the amount Meng was accused of receiving seemed low, compared with bribes of hundreds of millions of yuan (1 million yuan = U.S. $146,000) ascribed to much lower-ranking officials in China.<br><br>"If he really did accept bribes, then this probably wasn't the actual amount," Chen said. "County-level and district-level party secretaries get far larger sums than this."<br><br>"It's likely that something else is going on here."<br><br>Last month, France granted political asylum to Meng's wife Grace and the couple's two children, after she told police she was the target of an unsuccessful abduction attempt at the beginning of the year.<br><br>Meng went missing last year during a trip back to China.<br><br>He was placed under investigation for corruption at a secret location "on the outskirts of Beijing" after Interpol accepted his resignation with no questions asked on Oct. 7, 2018.<br><br>Interpol gave no reason for the resignation, nor did it make any public comment on the detention of its president. Meng had been elected to lead the international police agency until 2020.<br><br>Grace Meng, whose Chinese name is Gao Ge, was left behind in France with scant information, other than a social media message from her husband telling her to "wait for my call," and then a knife emoji signifying danger.<br><br>Grace Meng said recently that Chinese officials had presented "no proof whatsoever to back up their charges," and has said that she still fears kidnap attempts.<br><br>Overseas-based Chinese activists say China has a long track record in cross-border abductions.<br><br><b>Anti-corruption campaign</b><br><br>An independent Beijing-based scholar surnamed Song said Meng's prosecution, which will almost certainly result in a jail term, is another example of political prosecutions under the aegis of President Xi Jinping's anti-corruption campaign.<br><br>"If Meng Hongwei only took bribes of [U.S. $2 million], then he's probably the cleanest official [in China]," Song said.<br><br>"All this proves is that there is factional strife at the highest levels of Communist Party leadership, and that the anti-corruption campaign is selective, and depends on factional struggles," he said.<br><br>Reports suggest that Meng was appointed vice-minister for public security by disgraced former public security minister Zhou Yongkang, who rose to power at the head of China feared "stability maintenance" system,<br><br>Zhou was jailed for life by the Tianjin No. 1 Intermediate People's Court in June 2015, after being found guilty of bribe-taking, abuse of power, and disclosure of state secrets in a secret trial.<br><br>Zhou's sentence came rumors of a political coup attempt to topple Xi by him and jailed former Chongqing party chief Bo Xilai. China's securities regulator Liu Shiyu later told top finance officials during the 19th Party Congress in 2017 that senior figures had "conspired openly to usurp party leadership."<br><br>Earlier that year, Xi had accused five disgraced party officials, including Zhou and Bo, of involvement in "political conspiracies."<br><br><i><b>Reported by Qiao Long for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/trial-06202019111503.html/china-meng-hongwei-trial-june-2019.jpg/@@images/b7411214-8902-49bd-933e-eafb0e0e43cb.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;This handout photo released by the Tianjin No. 1 Intermediate Court shows former Interpol chief Meng Hongwei (C) during his trial at the court in Tianjin, June 20, 2019.&quot; title=&quot;This handout photo released by the Tianjin No. 1 Intermediate Court shows former Interpol chief Meng Hongwei (C) during his trial at the court in Tianjin, June 20, 2019.&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; width=&quot;622&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Calls Grow For an Independent Probe Into Police Violence During Hong Kong Protests</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/06/29/index/</id>
    <published>2019-06-30T04:00:09.970Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-30T05:06:58.488Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <img src="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/violence-06252019112640.html/china-injured2-062519.jpg/image" alt="Riot police surround an injured cameraman after firing tear gas at protesters in Hong Kong, June 12, 2019." title="Riot police surround an injured cameraman after firing tear gas at protesters in Hong Kong, June 12, 2019." height="349" width="620"><a id="more"></a>  <p>Authorities in Hong Kong on Tuesday faced a growing number of calls for a public inquiry into their handling of recent mass protests against plans to allow extraditions to mainland China, as chief executive Carrie Lam canceled a scheduled meeting of her cabinet.<br><br>Professional and religious organizations called on the government to set up an independent investigation committee to probe the events of June 12 and examine police actions, after Amnesty International said the city's police acted with unlawful force when using tear gas, rubber and textile bullets, and batons to disperse crowds of unarmed civilians on June 12.<br><br>They said the government's insistence that the Independent Police Complaints Council (IPCC) could handle any complaints was fundamentally flawed, as any complaints end up being investigated by the police themselves.<br><br>"The IPCC is itself part of the police force, and it's very easy to sympathize and see things from one's colleagues' point of view," Sing Ming, associate social sciences professor at the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, said.<br><br>Meanwhile, former colonial-era second-in-command Anson Chan hit out at Lam, saying she bears the greatest responsibility for the government's handling of the political crisis around planned amendments to the Fugitive Offenders Ordinance, which would allow alleged criminal suspects to be sent to face trial in mainland China.<br><br>Britain also urged Hong Kong to conduct an independent investigation into police actions on June 12.<br><br>"I today urge the Hong Kong SAR government to establish a robust, independent investigation into the violent scenes that we saw," foreign secretary Jeremy Hunt told members of parliament. "The outcome of that investigation will inform our assessment of future export license applications to the Hong Kong police."<br><br>Hunt said no new licenses for "crowd control equipment" would be issued to Hong Kong importers unless human rights concerns were addressed.<br><b><br>Clear hostility</b><br><br>Back in Hong Kong, barrister Geoffrey Yeung of the Progressive Lawyers Group, said police tactics in the face of mass protest need to be looked at across the board.<br><br>"We could see for example that there's clear hostility towards journalists or the protesters at the scene, whether there was something that went wrong," Yeung told government broadcaster RTHK. <br><br>"Was it because the police officers went off the guidelines or was it because the guidelines themselves were problematic?"<br><br>Hundreds of protesters once more converged on government buildings on Monday, following much larger civil disobedience action by thousands of people on Friday.<br><br>The government said it wouldn't be holding a scheduled Executive Council (ExCo) meeting, although protesters only targeted immigration and tax headquarters and the Legislative Council (LegCo), before dispersing peacefully.<br><br>"The chief executive was elected by just 1,200 people," a protester surnamed Chan told RFA on Monday, in reference to the Election Committee that is itself hand-picked by the ruling Chinese Communist Party. "That's why she needs to be held to account by the public."<br><br>"The trouble is that even if one or two million people take to the streets, the government doesn't have to answer to them, so I think that this movement ... is useful, but that it's not going to be enough," he said.<br><br><b>'We've already had this'</b><br><br>An employee surnamed Cheung who works at Revenue Tower said she is broadly supportive of the protest movement.<br><br>"I do basically support them, but I think we've already had this on Friday, and now they're doing it again, which I think is going to alienate a lot of people," Cheung said.<br><br>"So even though I support them, I don't now, because I think they should have left us some way to go out and buy food and come back in again."<br><br>Pro-democracy lawmakers accused Lam's administration of hiding from the public by canceling the ExCo meeting.<br><br>"When the government claims they want to connect with Hong Kong people, this is blatantly a disconnection with Hong Kong people," Civic Party leader Alvin Yeung told lawmakers in comments reported by RTHK.<br><br>"The conflict is still in the society about the extradition bill," he said. The government should face up to the conflict ... and not be hiding from the scene."<br><br>Pro-democracy camp convenor Claudia Mo said officials are very nervous following the mass civil disobedience actions of recent weeks.<br><br>"This government has become a joke for the Hong Kong community and the international community," Mo told reporters.<br><br><b>Business as usual</b><br><br>Development secretary Michael Wong said much official business is proceeding as normal, however.<br><br>"It's true that the social atmosphere right now is quite tense, and we think that if there is a chance for the society to relax a bit, for everyone to calm down, then we can be pragmatic and do our job," he said.<br><br>Meanwhile, the government is facing a legal challenge over the failure of special tactical unit police officers to display their identification numbers during clashes on June 12.<br><br>A local resident has applied for a judicial review after he was told to stop taking pictures of the protests by police, and is calling on the court to ban police officers from carrying out their duties without displaying a valid ID.<br><br><i><b>Reported by Gao Feng for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by Tseng Lap-yin for the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/violence-06252019112640.html/china-injured2-062519.jpg/image&quot; alt=&quot;Riot police surround an injured cameraman after firing tear gas at protesters in Hong Kong, June 12, 2019.&quot; title=&quot;Riot police surround an injured cameraman after firing tear gas at protesters in Hong Kong, June 12, 2019.&quot; height=&quot;349&quot; width=&quot;620&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
